<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Workshops on Records Sound the Same</title>
    <link>http://recordssoundthesame.com/services/workshops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workshops on Records Sound the Same</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <managingEditor>hello@recordssoundthesame.com (Records Sound the Same)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hello@recordssoundthesame.com (Records Sound the Same)</webMaster>
    <copyright>All content is copyright Records Sound the Same Ltd</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="http://recordssoundthesame.com/services/workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: An introduction to digital transformation</title>
      <link>http://recordssoundthesame.com/services/workshops/intro-to-digital-transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hello@recordssoundthesame.com (Records Sound the Same)</author>
      <guid>http://recordssoundthesame.com/services/workshops/intro-to-digital-transformation/</guid>
      <description>This one-day training workshop has been designed to give organisations a practical introduction to exercises which can help kick-start digital transformation projects, and make change happen.
Change takes many forms. Perhaps you’re looking to change your ways of working to better support customers, or to build internal capabilities, tools, and skills. You may be thinking about modernising older systems and processes, setting your digital strategy, or trying to work out the structure and roles your teams need… but feel you need a little bit of a helping hand to know that you’re thinking about the right things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Making the most of the modern web</title>
      <link>http://recordssoundthesame.com/services/workshops/making-the-most-of-the-modern-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hello@recordssoundthesame.com (Records Sound the Same)</author>
      <guid>http://recordssoundthesame.com/services/workshops/making-the-most-of-the-modern-web/</guid>
      <description>In this training workshop we’ll cover some of the exciting possibilities that the modern web brings us, and look at how these can bring benefits to both customers and your business itself.
You may have heard about “progressive web apps” (PWAs) but not really be sure what they are, or why some of the conversations around them (involving words like ‘service workers’, ’performance’, ‘offline’, or ‘progressive enhancement’) really matter &amp;mdash; this will help to change that, and give you the confidence you need to understand where they, and other modern web options, can fit into your strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>