<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How we can help on Records Sound the Same</title>
    <link>http://recordssoundthesame.com/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How we can help on Records Sound the Same</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <managingEditor>hello@recordssoundthesame.com (Records Sound the Same)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hello@recordssoundthesame.com (Records Sound the Same)</webMaster>
    <copyright>All content is copyright Records Sound the Same Ltd</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="http://recordssoundthesame.com/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Consultancy</title>
      <link>http://recordssoundthesame.com/services/consultancy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hello@recordssoundthesame.com (Records Sound the Same)</author>
      <guid>http://recordssoundthesame.com/services/consultancy/</guid>
      <description>Perhaps you need help scoping a project before it’s quite pinned down. Maybe you just need a little bit of advice every now and again, or want a specialist on-hand for a while. You may not even be sure what you need, and would like someone to come in and advise on direction before making any further commitments to defining your strategy. Either way, we can provide technology agnostic, ad-hoc support, where no questions are stupid and we promise to speak to you like normal humans instead of jargon-tactic nonsense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital transformation projects</title>
      <link>http://recordssoundthesame.com/services/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hello@recordssoundthesame.com (Records Sound the Same)</author>
      <guid>http://recordssoundthesame.com/services/project/</guid>
      <description>This service is for when you’ve got something in mind, and need help with making change happy. It could be that you’re updating older systems and processes; bringing in new technology to support a website. It could be that you’re exploring the need for a new digital product and want to run some quick validation. It may even be that you’re wanting to transform how the organisation works with digital, and trying to solve some internal problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reviews and audits</title>
      <link>http://recordssoundthesame.com/services/reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hello@recordssoundthesame.com (Records Sound the Same)</author>
      <guid>http://recordssoundthesame.com/services/reviews/</guid>
      <description>Rather than commit to a full programme of work, an easy first step is to opt for a one-off review. With this in mind, we offer a selection of reviews and audits to help you quickly and affordably kick-start some change.
A review can give you an initial, independent assessment of how things stand, identification of opportunities and areas of improvement, plus practical recommendations for next steps. The aim isn’t just to identify what could be better, but also why it’s important - you&amp;rsquo;ll also get some insight into industry best-practices and information that you may not have known about.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>